day-7

1] Stack
s = "ab*c**def"
stack = []
for ch in s:
    if ch == "*":
        stack = []  
    else:
        stack.append(ch)
output = "".join(stack)
print(output) 	

2]Back space string compare.

Given two strings s and t, return true if they are equal when both are typed into empty text editors. '#' means a backspace character.

Note that after backspacing an empty text, the text will continue empty.
Example 1:

Input: s = "ab#c", t = "ad#c"
Output: true
Explanation: Both s and t become "ac"

class Solution:
    def backspaceCompare(self, s: str, t: str) -> bool:
        def build(string):
            stack = []
            for ch in string:
                if ch == "#":
                    if stack:
                        stack.pop()
                else:
                    stack.append(ch)
            return "".join(stack)

        return build(s) == build(t)

3] Valid paranthesis

Given a string s containing just the characters '(', ')', '{', '}', '[' and ']', determine if the input string is valid.

An input string is valid if:

Open brackets must be closed by the same type of brackets.
Open brackets must be closed in the correct order.
Every close bracket has a corresponding open bracket of the same type.
 Example 1:

Input: s = "()"

Output: true

Example 2:

Input: s = "()[]{}"

Output: true

Example 3:

Input: s = "(]"

Output: false

class Solution:
    def isValid(self, s: str) -> bool:
        stack = []
        for ch in s:
            if ch in "({[":
                stack.append(ch)
            else:
                if not stack:
                    return False
                top = stack[-1]
                if ch == ')' and top == '(':
                    stack.pop()
                elif ch == ']' and top == '[':
                    stack.pop()
                elif ch == '}' and top == '{':
                    stack.pop()
                else:
                    return False
        return not stack

4] Next Greater Element.

The next greater element of some element x in an array is the first greater element that is to the right of x in the same array.

You are given two distinct 0-indexed integer arrays nums1 and nums2, where nums1 is a subset of nums2.

For each 0 <= i < nums1.length, find the index j such that nums1[i] == nums2[j] and determine the next greater element of nums2[j] in nums2. If there is no next greater element, then the answer for this query is -1.

Return an array ans of length nums1.length such that ans[i] is the next greater element as described above.

 Example 1:

Input: nums1 = [4,1,2], nums2 = [1,3,4,2]
Output: [-1,3,-1]
Explanation: The next greater element for each value of nums1 is as follows:
- 4 is underlined in nums2 = [1,3,4,2]. There is no next greater element, so the answer is -1.
- 1 is underlined in nums2 = [1,3,4,2]. The next greater element is 3.
- 2 is underlined in nums2 = [1,3,4,2]. There is no next greater element, so the answer is -1.

class Solution:
    def nextGreaterElement(self, nums1: List[int], nums2: List[int]) -> List[int]:
        d={}
        stack=[]
        for curr in nums2:
            while stack and stack[-1]<curr:
                ele=stack.pop()
                d[ele]=currl
            stack.append(curr)
        while stack:
            d[stack.pop()]=-1
        res=[]
        for i in nums1:
            res.append(d[i])
        return res

5]Number of students unable to eat lunch.

The school cafeteria offers circular and square sandwiches at lunch break, referred to by numbers 0 and 1 respectively. All students stand in a queue. Each student either prefers square or circular sandwiches.

The number of sandwiches in the cafeteria is equal to the number of students. The sandwiches are placed in a stack. At each step:

If the student at the front of the queue prefers the sandwich on the top of the stack, they will take it and leave the queue.
Otherwise, they will leave it and go to the queue's end.
This continues until none of the queue students want to take the top sandwich and are thus unable to eat.

You are given two integer arrays students and sandwiches where sandwiches[i] is the type of the i​​​​​​th sandwich in the stack (i = 0 is the top of the stack) and students[j] is the preference of the j​​​​​​th student in the initial queue (j = 0 is the front of the queue). Return the number of students that are unable to eat.
Example 1:

Input: students = [1,1,0,0], sandwiches = [0,1,0,1]
Output: 0 
Explanation:
- Front student leaves the top sandwich and returns to the end of the line making students = [1,0,0,1].
- Front student leaves the top sandwich and returns to the end of the line making students = [0,0,1,1].
- Front student takes the top sandwich and leaves the line making students = [0,1,1] and sandwiches = [1,0,1].
- Front student leaves the top sandwich and returns to the end of the line making students = [1,1,0].
- Front student takes the top sandwich and leaves the line making students = [1,0] and sandwiches = [0,1].
- Front student leaves the top sandwich and returns to the end of the line making students = [0,1].
- Front student takes the top sandwich and leaves the line making students = [1] and sandwiches = [1].
- Front student takes the top sandwich and leaves the line making students = [] and sandwiches = [].
Hence all students are able to eat.

class Solution:
    def countStudents(self, students: List[int], sandwiches: List[int]) -> int:
        n=len(students)
        while students and sandwiches and sandwiches[0] in students:
            if students[0]!=sandwiches[0]:
                students.append(students.pop(0))
            else:
                students.pop(0)
                sandwiches.pop(0)
                n-=1
            return n

6] Daily Temperature.

Given an array of integers temperatures represents the daily temperatures, return an array answer such that answer[i] is the number of days you have to wait after the ith day to get a warmer temperature. If there is no future day for which this is possible, keep answer[i] == 0 instead.
Example 1:
Input: temperatures = [73,74,75,71,69,72,76,73]
Output: [1,1,4,2,1,1,0,0]

class Solution:
    def dailyTemperatures(self, temperatures: List[int]) -> List[int]:
        st = []
        res = [0] * len(temperatures)

        for i in range(len(temperatures)):
            while st and temperatures[i] > temperatures[st[-1]]:
                idx = st.pop()
                res[idx] = i - idx
            st.append(i)
        
        return res

7]Make the string Great

Given a string s of lower and upper case English letters.

A good string is a string which doesn't have two adjacent characters s[i] and s[i + 1] where:

0 <= i <= s.length - 2
s[i] is a lower-case letter and s[i + 1] is the same letter but in upper-case or vice-versa.
To make the string good, you can choose two adjacent characters that make the string bad and remove them. You can keep doing this until the string becomes good.

Return the string after making it good. The answer is guaranteed to be unique under the given constraints.

Notice that an empty string is also good.

Example 1:

Input: s = "leEeetcode"
Output: "leetcode"
Explanation: In the first step, either you choose i = 1 or i = 2, both will result "leEeetcode" to be reduced to "leetcode".

class Solution:
    def makeGood(self, s: str) -> str:

        stack = []
        for ch in s:
            if stack and stack[-1] != ch and stack[-1].lower() == ch.lower():
                stack.pop() 
            else:
                stack.append(ch)
        return "".join(stack)